The Fab Four without the Mop Tops
That Thing You Do! is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Tom Hanks.
A Pennsylvania band scores a hit in 1964 and rides the star-making
machinery as long as it can, with lots of help from its manager.
But behind the scenes, the group’s sudden fame tests their strength, their maturity and responsibility,
and their ability to resist the temptations that money and notoriety always make possible.
Mr. White, played by Tom Hanks.
Guy Patterson, played by Tom Everett Scott.
Faye Dolan, played by Liv Tyler.
Jimmy Mattingly, played by Johnathon Schaech.
Lenny Haise, played by Steve Zahn.
T.B. Player, played by Ethan Embry.
That Thing You Do!
is a 1996 American comedy-drama film written and directed by Tom
Hanks, in his feature writing and directorial debut.
Set in 1960s rock and roll culture, it chronicles the rise and fall of a fictional one-hit wonder pop band and stars Tom Everett Scott in his film debut
along with Johnathon Schaech, Steve Zahn, and Ethan Embry as the band's members, with Liv Tyler and Hanks appearing in supporting roles.
Its production and music are key to its narrative, with original scores by a
collaboration of artists including Hanks, Adam Schlesinger, and Howard Shore.
The soundtrack peaked at #21 on the Billboard 200 albums chart,
featuring a mix of diegetic and non-diegetic tracks.
The cast practiced for weeks to perform convincingly on camera,
blurring the lines between reality and fiction.
Despite being well received by critics, receiving several accolades, and producing a musical hit with the title song, which was nominated for an Academy Award
and a Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song, the film was a commercial disappointment, grossing $34.6 million against a $26 million budget.
It has since garnered a cult following.
The film explores themes of pop star, pennsylvania, usa, record
label, recording studio, battle of the bands.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.